YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series IV. Constituent Groups
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. CONSTITUENT GROUPS
  - Subseries D. Teenage and Younger Girls
    - Programs and Projects
      - National Youthworker Education Project
        - Required readings, 1976, n.d. (Box 557, Folder 8)
      - Neighborhood Youth Consumer Education Project, 1972-75 (Box 557, Folder 9)
      - Summer Youth Demonstration Project
        - Report to U.S. Department of Labor, Nov 1967
          - Vol. 1 (Box 557, Folder 10)
          - Vol. 2 (Box 557, Folder 11)
          - Abridged report (Box 558, Folder 1)
      - Teen Counseling Project, YWCA Resource Center on Women and Bank Street College of Education
        - General, 1974 (Box 558, Folder 2)
        - "Attention is Needed, Action is Called For: Teen Women Tell About Their Needs," report on Teen Counseling Project Workshops, 1974 (Box 558, Folder 3)
        - "Cause for Action: Report of the Proposal for Determining the Needs of Teen-Age Women and the Educational Services they Require in a Changing World," ca. 1973 (Box 558, Folder 4)
        - Summary Report, "A Job at the End: Guidelines for Teen Counseling, Training and Career Development," 1975 (Box 558, Folder 5)
      - Teen Pregnancy Prevention Program
        - General, 1994, n.d. (Box 558, Folder 6)
        - Information packet, circa 1989 (Box 558, Folder 7)
        - "It's Okay to Say No Way" brochure and leader's guide to music video, 1986 (Box 558, Folder 8)
        - List of community Associations' programs, 1995 (Box 558, Folder 9)
        - P.A.C.T. (Peer Approach Counseling by Teens)
          - Cleveland YWCA: curriculum packet, circa 1980 (Box 558, Folder 10)
          - Taking the Lead with P.A.C.T.: Peer Education in Sexuality and Health, National YWCA program manual, 1989 (Box 558, Folder 11)
      - Teen Pregnancy Reduction Program: proposal to Ford Foundation, 1983 (Box 558, Folder 12)
      - Teen Sexuality Education Project: final report, 1982, [see also Elizabeth Steel Genné Papers] (Box 559, Folder 1)
      - Teens for Aids Prevention (T.A.P.), Center for Population Options and YWCAs of Atlanta, GA, Hartford, CT, and Greater Milwaukee, WI, 1990 (Box 559, Folder 2-3)
      - Tomorrow's Women, 1990-91, n.d. (Box 559, Folder 4)
      - Y-Teen Roll Call Week: publicity kit, 1949 (Box 559, Folder 5)
      - YWCA Teen Week: publicity kit, 1988 (Box 559, Folder 6)
      - Young Women's Employment Training Project (YWETP)
        - General, 1984-87 (Box 559, Folder 7)
        - State-of-the-Art Paper and literature review by Harriet G. Dockstader, 1986 (Box 559, Folder 8)
      - Youth Employment Project (YEP), National Collaboration for Youth, 1979-83 (Box 559, Folder 9)
      - Youth Development Program
        - General, 1991-2000 (Box 559, Folder 10)
        - Notebook, circa 1999 (includes information about YWCA/PepsiCo Girls Leadership Program, Mott Pregnancy Prevention Program, and TechGRYRLS) (Box 559, Folder 11-13)
        - TechGYRLS
          - General, 1997-2002, n.d. (Box 560, Folder 1)
          - Program manual, 2002 (Box 560, Folder 2)
          - Training manual, n.d. (Box 560, Folder 3)
          - Community Association programs
            - Winnetka Elementary School, Dallas, Texas, 1998 (Box 560, Folder 4-5)
            - Riverside, California: Challenges of Youth, 1998 (Box 560, Folder 6)
            - Western Massachusetts: Our Health, Our Futures, 1999 (Box 560, Folder 7)
      - Youth Workers Team Learning Project
        - Proposals to the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1969-70 (Box 560, Folder 8)
        - Final Report, 1972 (Box 560, Folder 9)
    - Publications
      - Character, citizenship, and religion
        - General, 1915-69 (Box 561, Folder 1-5)
        - "Life and I" by Oolooah Burner, 1926-42 (Box 561, Folder 6)
      - Handbooks and year books for Girl Reserves/Y-Teens
        - The Girl Reserves: A Guide for Every Loyal Blue Triangle Girl, 1919-23 (Box 561, Folder 7)
        - Treasure Trove, 1921 (Box 561, Folder 8)
        - The Girl's Every Day Book, 1926, 1928 (Box 561, Folder 9-10)
        - The Girls' Yearbook, 1917-30 (Box 562, Folder 1-5)
        - My Own Book, 194 (Box 563, Folder 1)
        - Girls Yearbook, 1945 (Box 563, Folder 2)
        - Teens: How to Meet Your Problems, 1951 (Box 563, Folder 3)
        - Our Yearbook: Y-Teen, 1951-62 (Box 563, Folder 4)
        - High School/Boarding School
          - General, 1924, 1928 (Box 563, Folder 5-6)
          - Suggested Constitutions for secondary school Associations, 1918, 1920 (Box 563, Folder 7)
      - The Inch Library
        - First Inch, 1915, circa 1920 (Box 563, Folder 8-9)
        - Second Inch, 1916-circa 1920 (Box 564, Folder 1-2)
        - Third Inch, 1918 (Box 564, Folder 3-4)
      - Manuals and training materials for teen committee, group leaders, and staff
        - General
          - 1918-21 (Box 564, Folder 5-6)
          - 1922-47 (Box 565, Folder 1-8)
          - 1948-64 (Box 566, Folder 1-6)
        - Committee, 1917-63 (Box 566, Folder 7-11)
        - Parents groups, 1937-45 (Box 566, Folder 12)
        - Junior High School Advisers, 1938, 1943 (Box 567, Folder 1-2)
        - Registered Clubs, 1929-65 (Box 567, Folder 3-4)
        - Volunteers, 1949, n.d. (Box 567, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous
        - 1917-62 (Box 567, Folder 6)
        - Banquet Suggestions for Girls and Their Mothers, 1937, 1944 (Box 567, Folder 7)
        - Baby Sitters: A Basic Training Manual, 1956-62 (Box 567, Folder 8)
        - The Home-Town Vacation, 1933 (Box 567, Folder 9)
      - Program materials
        - General
          - 1917-19 (Box 567, Folder 10)
          - A Program Book for Girl Reserves, 1932 (Box 567, Folder 11)
          - Program Emphases Interpreted for Younger Girl Conferences and Club Work in the YWCAs, 1936 (Box 567, Folder 12)
          - Another Program Book for Girl Reserves, 1936, 1940 (Box 567, Folder 13)
          - Public Affairs Size 16, 1939-40 (Box 568, Folder 1)
          - Girl Reserve Program for Today, 1943 (Box 568, Folder 2)
          - Program Ideas for Y-Teens, 1946 (Box 568, Folder 3)
          - Youth Together and Youth on Trial: Program Ideas for YMCA and YWCA High School Youth Groups, 1947-48 (Box 568, Folder 4)
          - 1950-82 (Box 568, Folder 5)
        - Health, sex education, and personal relations
          - 1921-65 (Box 568, Folder 6-15)
        - High school, 1919-20 (Box 568, Folder 16)
        - Interracial issues
          - "Pudge" series, 1936-42 (Box 568, Folder 17-19)
          - "Help in Program Planning for American Indian Girls in YWCA and Girl Reserve Groups," n.d. (Box 569, Folder 1)
        - Leadership, 1938-46 (Box 569, Folder 2-3)
        - World Fellowship, 1932-36 (Box 569, Folder 4-5)
        - Younger girls (grade and junior high school), 1916-47 (Box 569, Folder 6-7)
      - Serials
        - The Girls' Work Book Shelf, 1918-22 [bound copies] (Box 569, Folder 8)
        - The Girl Reserve Bookshelf: A Resource for Advisers of Girls Activities, 1923-25 [photocopies] (Box 570, Folder 1)
        - The Bookshelf: A Bulletin for Leaders of Younger Girls/Girl Reserve Advisers/Teenage Program Advisers/Advisers of Y-Teens [bound copies]
          - 1925-Dec 1942 (Box 570, Folder 2-4)
          - 1943-winter 1964/65 (Box 571, Folder 1-4)
          - Spr 1965-Spr 1968 (Box 572, Folder 1)
        - Y-Teen Scene, summer 1968-73 (Box 572, Folder 2)
        - National Adolescent Sexuality Brief, 1983-84 (Box 572, Folder 3)
        - Newsletter for Teen-Age Program Directors, 1950-52 (Box 572, Folder 4)
        - Teen Brief, 1983-85 (Box 572, Folder 5)
        - Teen Freedom, 1973-75 (Box 572, Folder 6)
    - Reference materials
      - General, 1922-65 (Box 572, Folder 7)
      - Beside Our Campfires, A Girl Reserve's Goodnight by Suzanne Weddell, 1925 (Box 572, Folder 8)
      - Understanding the Adolescent Girl by Grace Loucks Elliott, 1930, 1949 (Box 573, Folder 1)
    - Reports
      - Miscellaneous, 1927-97 (Box 573, Folder 2)
      - Department
        - Summary of Work, 1927-28 (Box 573, Folder 3-4)
        - Annual Meeting, 4-6 Dec 1929 (Box 573, Folder 5)
        - Biennial Report, Jan 1930 (Box 573, Folder 6)
        - Girl Reserve Secretarial Seminar, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 7)
        - Memorandum on status of Girl Reserve work, 1924 (Box 573, Folder 8)
        - Secretaries' annual and general reports
          - Esther A. Dayman, 1923, 1925 (Box 573, Folder 9)
          - Gertrude Gogin, 1927 (Box 573, Folder 10)
          - Rhoda Harris, 1925 (Box 573, Folder 11)
          - Bella Taylor McKnight, 1929, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 12)
          - Helen McNeil, 1929-31 (Box 573, Folder 13)
          - Helen E. Price, 1923-24 (Box 573, Folder 14)
          - Margaret A. West, 1922 (Box 573, Folder 15)
          - Edith G. Wilson, 1929-31 (Box 573, Folder 16)
          - Georgia Wittich, 1923 (Box 573, Folder 17)
        - Summary of problems relating to work plans of Girl Reserve staff, 1936-37 (Box 573, Folder 18)
        - Summary of work plans, Girl Reserve staff, proposed for 1937-38 (Box 573, Folder 19)
      - Recommendations to Leadership Division Committee, Jan 1940 (Box 573, Folder 20)
      - Summer School, Berkeley, 1927 (Box 573, Folder 21)
      - Visitation
        - Alabama, 1923, 1926 (Box 573, Folder 22)
        - Arizona, 1923-24, 1927 (Box 573, Folder 23)
        - Arkansas, 1929-31 (Box 573, Folder 24)
        - California, 1923-28 (Box 573, Folder 25)
        - Canal Zone, 1930 (Box 573, Folder 26)
        - Colorado, 1923-31 (Box 573, Folder 27)
        - Connecticut, 1923-31 (Box 573, Folder 28)
        - Delaware, 1923-24, 1930 (Box 573, Folder 29)
        - District of Columbia, 1923, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 30)
        - Florida, 1923-26 (Box 573, Folder 31)
        - Georgia, 1923, 1929 (Box 573, Folder 32)
        - Idaho, 1923, 1927 (Box 573, Folder 33)
        - Illinois, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 34)
        - Iowa, 1926-31, [see also Rural Communities Committee] (Box 573, Folder 35)
        - Kansas, 1928, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 36)
        - Kentucky, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 37)
        - Louisiana, 1926,1931 (Box 573, Folder 38)
        - Maine, 1924 (Box 573, Folder 39)
        - Maryland, 1925, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 40)
        - Massachusetts, 1923-25 (Box 573, Folder 41)
        - Minnesota, 1930 (Box 573, Folder 42)
        - Missouri, 1928-31 (Box 573, Folder 43)
        - Montana, 1923, 1927 (Box 573, Folder 44)
        - Nebraska, 1930 (Box 573, Folder 45)
        - Nevada, 1923 (Box 573, Folder 46)
        - New Hampshire, 1924-25 (Box 573, Folder 47)
        - New Jersey, 1923-31 (Box 573, Folder 48)
        - New Mexico, 1924 (Box 573, Folder 49)
        - New York, 1923-31 (Box 573, Folder 50)
        - North Carolina, 1924-29 (Box 573, Folder 51)
        - Ohio, 1931 (Box 573, Folder 52)
        - Oklahoma, 1930-31 (Box 573, Folder 53)
        - Oregon, 1923-28 (Box 573, Folder 54)
        - Pennsylvania, 1923-31 (Box 574, Folder 1)
        - Rhode Island, 1924-25 (Box 574, Folder 2)
        - South Carolina, 1924, 1926 (Box 574, Folder 3)
        - South Dakota, 1930 (Box 574, Folder 4)
        - Tennessee, 1923, 1929 (Box 574, Folder 5)
        - Texas, 1930-31 (Box 574, Folder 6)
        - Utah, 1923, 1927 (Box 574, Folder 7)
        - Virginia, 1924-27 (Box 574, Folder 8)
        - Washington, 1923-27 (Box 574, Folder 9)
        - West Virginia, 1923-27 (Box 574, Folder 10)
        - Wisconsin, 1930 (Box 574, Folder 11)
        - Wyoming, 1927 (Box 574, Folder 12)
      - What are the needs and problems of the modern younger girl? How are they being met? ca. 1928 (Box 574, Folder 13)
      - Y-Teens and Y-Teens Leaders meetings at national convention, 1955 (Box 574, Folder 14)
    - Studies
      - Best Girl Reserve Methods: compilation of responses to questionnaire, 1940 (Box 574, Folder 15)
      - The Job of the Younger Girls' Secretary in the YWCA, 1944 (Box 574, Folder 16)
      - Local Work, summary of a study, 1927-28 (Box 574, Folder 17)
      - Looking for Gremlins in Girl Reserve Clubs, 1944 (Box 574, Folder 18)
      - Major Problems Study, 1939-40
        - Central region (Box 574, Folder 19)
        - Northeast region (Box 574, Folder 20)
        - Northwest region (Box 574, Folder 21)
        - Southern region (Box 574, Folder 22)
        - Southwest and Rocky Mountain regions (Box 574, Folder 23)
        - Western region (Box 574, Folder 24)
      - [Girl Reserve] Section Studies
        - Correspondence, 1927-29 (Box 574, Folder 25)
        - Reports, 1928-30 (Box 574, Folder 26)
      - Survey: Are Teen-Agers Responsible Citizens?: report 1954 (Box 575, Folder 1)
      - Survey of Adolescent Programs in YWCA member associations, 1998-99 (includes other corr re Youth-related programs), [see also Record Group 8 for an earlier, similar survey] (Box 575)
        - Arkansas, El Dorado (Box 575, Folder 2)
        - California
          - Contra Costa County (Box 575, Folder 3)
          - Harbor Area (Box 575, Folder 4)
          - Los Angeles, Greater (Box 575, Folder 5)
          - Mid-Peninsula (Box 575, Folder 6)
          - Riverside (Box 575, Folder 7)
          - San Francisco (Box 575, Folder 8)
          - San Gabriel Valley (Box 575, Folder 9)
          - Santa Clara Valley (Box 575, Folder 10)
          - Santa Monica (Box 575, Folder 11)
          - Watsonville (Box 575, Folder 12)
          - West End (Box 575, Folder 13)
        - Colorado: Boulder (Box 575, Folder 14)
        - Connecticut: Greenwich (Box 575, Folder 15)
        - Delaware: New Castle County (Box 575, Folder 16)
        - Florida: Miami, Greater (Box 575, Folder 17)
        - Georgia: Atlanta, Greater (Box 575, Folder 18)
        - Illinois
          - Elgin (Box 575, Folder 19)
          - Evanston/North Shore (Box 575, Folder 20)
          - Rockford (Box 575, Folder 21)
          - Sauk Valley (Box 575, Folder 22)
        - Indiana
          - Evansville (Box 575, Folder 23)
          - Fort Wayne (Box 575, Folder 24)
        - Kansas
          - Salina (Box 575, Folder 25)
          - Topeka (Box 575, Folder 26)
        - Massachusetts
          - Central Massachusetts (Box 575, Folder 27)
          - Haverhill (Box 575, Folder 28)
          - Western Massachusetts (Box 575, Folder 29)
        - Maine: Mount Desert Island (Box 575, Folder 30)
        - Michigan
          - Bay County (Box 575, Folder 31)
          - Kalamazoo (Box 575, Folder 32)
        - Minnesota: Mankato (Box 575, Folder 33)
        - Missouri
          - Kansas City (Box 576, Folder 1)
          - St. Joseph (Box 576, Folder 2)
          - St. Louis (Box 576, Folder 3)
        - Montana: Billings (Box 576, Folder 4)
        - Nebraska: Lincoln (Box 576, Folder 5)
        - New Hampshire: Manchester (Box 576, Folder 6)
        - New Jersey
          - Essex and West Hudson (Box 576, Folder 7)
          - Hudson County (Box 576, Folder 8)
          - Montclair and North Essex (Box 576, Folder 9)
          - Trenton (Box 576, Folder 10)
        - New Mexico: Albuquerque (Box 576, Folder 11)
        - New York
          - City of New York, Flushing Branch (Box 576, Folder 12)
          - Cortland (Box 576, Folder 13)
          - Elmira and the Twin Tiers (Box 576, Folder 14)
          - Jamestown (Box 576, Folder 15)
          - Schenectady (Box 576, Folder 16)
          - The Tonawandas and Niagara Frontier (Box 576, Folder 17)
          - Ulster County (Box 576, Folder 18)
          - Westfield (Box 576, Folder 19)
          - White Plains and Central Westchester (Box 576, Folder 20)
        - North Carolina
          - Central Carolinas (Box 576, Folder 21)
          - Greensboro (Box 576, Folder 22)
          - High Point (Box 576, Folder 23)
          - Wake County (Box 576, Folder 24)
        - Oregon: Portland (Box 576, Folder 15)
        - Ohio
          - Akron (Box 576, Folder 26)
          - Cincinnati (Box 576, Folder 27)
          - Cleveland (Box 576, Folder 28)
          - Dayton (Box 576, Folder 29)
          - Lima (Box 576, Folder 30)
          - Lorain (Box 576, Folder 31)
          - Salem (Box 577, Folder 1)
          - Toledo (Box 577, Folder 2)
          - Youngstown (Box 577, Folder 3)
        - Pennsylvania
          - Bradford (Box 577, Folder 4)
          - Carlisle (Box 577, Folder 5)
          - Gettysburg and Adams County (Box 577, Folder 6)
          - Lancaster (Box 577, Folder 7)
          - Pottstown (Box 577, Folder 8)
          - West Chester, Greater (Box 577, Folder 9)
        - Rhode Island, Greater (Box 577, Folder 10)
        - South Carolina
          - Greenville (Box 577, Folder 11)
          - The Midlands (Box 577, Folder 12)
        - Tennessee
          - Blount County (Box 577, Folder 13)
          - Bristol (Box 577, Folder 14)
          - Knoxville (Box 577, Folder 15)
          - Memphis (Box 577, Folder 16)
          - Middle Tennessee (Box 577, Folder 17)
        - Texas
          - El Paso del Norte Region (Box 577, Folder 18)
          - San Antonio (Box 577, Folder 19)
        - Washington
          - Seattle (Box 577, Folder 20)
          - Tacoma-Pierce County (Box 577, Folder 21)
        - West Virginia: Wheeling (Box 577, Folder 22)
        - Wisconsin
          - Coulee Region (Box 577, Folder 23)
          - Green Bay (Box 577, Folder 24)
          - Milwaukee, Greater (Box 577, Folder 25)
          - Waukesha (Box 577, Folder 26)
          - Wausau (Box 577, Folder 27)
      - Work with Younger Girls in the YWCA by Helen E. Davis, 1932-34 (Box 577, Folder 28)
      - Youth Work Techniques Development Centers: proposal to U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1970 (Box 577, Folder 29)
    - OVERSIZE
      - Miscellaneous (Box 578)
        - Miscellaneous items from local Girl Reserve Clubs, 1925-38 (Box 578, Folder 1)
        - Hand-Book, YWCA of Northfield Seminary, 1894-95 (Box 578, Folder 2)
        - Maria de Jesus Lopez, Girl Reserve scrapbook, 1941-43, Mexican Community House Girl Reserves, El Paso, Texas (Box 578, Folder 3-6)
      - Publications
        - Sleeve boxes for Inch Library (Box 579)
        - Preservation copies of Bookshelf [mostly unbound][DO NOT USE] (Box 580)
          - 1918-43 (Box 580, Folder 1-13)
          - 1944-68 (Box 581, Folder 1-13)
          - Preservation copies of Y-Teen Scene 1968-1973 (Box 581, Folder 14-16)
  - Subseries E. Young Adults
    - Home Women: general, 1948-49 (Box 583, Folder 1)
    - YW-Wives: general, 1950-57, n.d. (Box 583, Folder 2)
    - Young Adult Program
      - General, 1950-78, n.d. (Box 583, Folder 3)
      - Committee/Council, 1951-52, 1961 (Box 583, Folder 4)
      - National Young Adult Conference, Nov 1969: Program Memo to Staff, Feb 1970 (Box 583, Folder 5)
      - Publications
        - Program Papers 1966, I. The YWCA Serves Young Adults Under 25 1966 (Box 584, Folder 1)
        - Young Adult Working Papers, fall 1968 (Box 584, Folder 2)
        - Young Adults and the YWCA (booklets 1-7), 1953-54 (Box 584, Folder 3)
        - Young Adults and the YWCA (quarterly), 1954-58 (Box 584, Folder 4-7)
        - Young Adults in the YWCA: Program Guide, 1959 (Box 584, Folder 8)
        - Young Adults in the 1960s: Changing Lives, Changing Program, 1964 (Box 584, Folder 9)
    - Young Women Committed to Action
      - General, 1970-74, n.d. (Box 584, Folder 10)
      - Continuing Committee, 1973-74 (Box 584, Folder 11)
      - Assembly, Mar 1973 (Box 584, Folder 12)
      - Publications
        - "Basic Notebook," 1974 (Box 584, Folder 13)
        - "Behind Every Face There is a Soul" Program Tool (poster book), winter 1967 (Box 584, Folder 14)
        - Newsletter, Sep 1971, n.d. (Box 584, Folder 15)
        - "YWCA Program is Doing Not Talking," Oct 1970 (Box 584, Folder 16)
      - Workshops
        - Affirmative Process Skills Development, Dec 1972 (Box 584, Folder 17)
        - Mobilize, Dec 1974 (Box 584, Folder 18)
    - Youth Constituencies Unit
      - General, 1974 (Box 584, Folder 19)
      - Manual "New Young Women in the YWCA: a manual for mobilizing young women in the YWCA through a self-renewal program process," 1975 (Box 584, Folder 20)